For example, the cherry blossom petals, the summer
night sky, the moon above the power line,
the snow falling in the city, the railroad
crossing, public transportation, radio waves, I'm always
looking for the signs of that time somewhere.
I'm Touno.
Nice to meet you, I'm Touno
do.
It's a pretty well-organized
design, isn't it?
But I'd like you to see all
sorts of places.
So I made a memo.
I see.
It's interesting when there are various words.
What would you write, Mr. Tonno?
Me?
There are more than 55,000 words that
people meet in their lifetime.
If you had to choose just one word
to leave behind...
Just one word...
You guys again?
How many times do we have to do
this?
What's going on?
I'm sorry, I got carried away again.
It's impossible.
There's no change in use, is there?
Let's calm down for now.
Let's talk while we eat.
Where are you going?
What do you mean?
We're in the middle of a meeting.
Oh, it's fine.
It's not good to bother you.
Let's go.
Hey, where's your watch?
Oh, I put it in my bag.
What?
I want to fix my watch, too.
I'll go get it for you.
No, that's not what I meant at
all.
Misuno-san, your heels...
I'm going to...
I'll go get it.
I'll leave it to you, then.
She doesn't talk at all.
Only business calls?
She's next to Misuno-san,
so she talks a little more freely.
I don't think she wants to talk
at work.
Oh, I see.
Then I'm going to go out for
a bit.
It's 8 o'clock, so we're
going to move out.
I'll go to the casino first.
Thank you.
Thank you for
your hard work.
Hey.
Oh.
It's been a while.
Yeah, it's been a while.
How long has it been since we worked
together?
Five years, I think.
Oh, that long.
How old are you?
I'm 29.
You know, roughness is good in life.
It's beautiful.
There's no waste.
Thank you.
Aren't you going to my party?
I'm going.
When this is over.
Okay, then.
Huh?
There's no one else?
Oh.
Oh, never mind.
Let's go.
Oh, sorry.
Just a minute.
Thank you for your hard work.
See you tomorrow.
How was
the shoot?
The reason Jinji chose her was because
of her personality.
Don't be scared.
Yes.
How's your team doing?
Well...
There's a lot of unproductive
talk.
Oh.
If it's an email, it's 30
seconds.
If it's lunch, it's an hour.
And there's a lot of nonsense.
What kind of nonsense?
People who have nothing to do with work
talk.
You're still the same.
The train window is rattling.
I'm leaving the city where I live.
There was no one to see me off.
The scenery I know and the scenery I
don't know.
Like the breath deceiving me.
Before I knew it, it's changing.
My body is still stopped.
It's over 100 kilometers per hour.
It's a strange storm to think about.
I'm still stopped.
I can't keep quiet about something so
strange.
I remember that I was alone soon.
I wonder if everyone bought their
own tickets.
I wonder if I've been carrying my
story so far.
When are you going to take a break
with Berry?
I don't know.
You don't know the season, do you?
What?
You're the only one who can do
it for a long time.
That's true.
Oh, it's here.
Can I take a look at it slowly?
Yes.
Shi-chan.
Midori-san.
Thank you for your hard work.
Are you all right?
I'm fine.
I borrowed that movie the other day and
watched it.
Really?
Where was it?
You said you were going to cry.
I don't remember the content of the
movie at all.
I don't remember the content.
But I remember the atmosphere and smell of
the movie theater when I saw it.
When I was walking around town.
And I cried.
Don't you have it?
Do you mean you don't remember it?
I don't remember it.
I don't have it.
You don't have it?
No, it's okay.
I feel like I'm alive now.
Is that so?
That's right.
Teacher, please.
Please break it in half.
In half?
I see.
What should I do?
Are you coming home?
I brought my work home today.
I see.
It's okay.
Don't push yourself too hard.
Okay.
See you tomorrow at work.
Be careful.
Thank you.
Bye.
There are so many cardboard boxes.
It's done.
This one is done, too.
That's great.
Do you have a place to put this
on?
Thank you.
If you have a place to put it
on.
This is good.
Is it?
It's cute.
I'm glad.
Thank you, everyone.
As expected of you, Shino.
You put a spotlight on a dumpling.
I'll put this on.
But why do you like such disgusting things?
That's a good question.
I've always been good at finding dumplings.
I was a kid who only looked down.
That kid must have been looking up all
the time.
That's right.
There are a lot.
I don't know.
Maybe it's water or sugar.
By the way, did you know it's
0.
0003%?
What's that?
The probability of people meeting each other.
It's not that low, is it?
I met an entertainer the other day.
Who?
I don't know.
I don't know his name.
That's it.
I'm sorry.
Did you go to the NTSC?
I went to the NTSC because
I got a cream.
By train?
You can't take the train, can you?
I'm sorry.
I fell down on the way.
I thought I'd be fine if I
took the medicine.
But I can't.
By the way, I haven't seen an
elementary school student in a long time.
Elementary school?
Yeah.
The uniform hasn't changed at all.
I didn't know there was a uniform
in elementary school.
Huh?
We've talked about it, haven't we?
You know, I've been a private student
since elementary school.
Oh, I see.
What about you, Tono?
What kind of elementary school was it?
Well, I've been transferred several times.
Oh, you were a transfer student.
I didn't know that.
I was transferred by my parents.
Oh, I see.
That's why you like to move.
Here you are.
Thank you.
Can I put it on?
Yeah.
Next is the weekly report.
You know, Tono.
Yeah.
It's easy to be with me, isn
't it?
What?
Yeah.
It's easy, but it's not fun,
is it?
No way.
I don't know.
It's not fun, but it's easy
for me, too.
I wonder if we're similar.
What do you mean?
If I say I don't care more
than necessary, no one will step in.
No one will step in.
People will take care of me because I
'm that kind of girl.
They'll keep a certain distance.
That's the easiest way, isn't it?
It's not fun, but it's easy.
It's unfair, isn't it?
Be careful on your way home.
For the
past few years, I wanted to move forward.
I wanted to touch what I couldn't
reach.
I didn't know what that meant.
I just kept working.
This is a souvenir.
I'll give it to you.
Thank you.
I used to be so serious and determined,
but I lost it.
When I knew I was at my limit,
I quit my job.
I didn't want to get too close
to anyone.
I didn't want to stay in one
place.
I wanted to be able to be fine
Who's the transfer student?
A girl.
I've never seen her before.
I saw her.
I saw her, too.
Is she a transfer student?
Yes, she is.
I don't know her.
Akari?
I'm waiting for my lunch.
You can't bring your lunch.
Can I bring it?
No, you can't.
You can't bring it.
I'll be fine.
Classmate.
Did you know that the sound of the
train changes little by little every day?
No.
I'm sorry.
It's nothing.
Why is it different?
Is it because of the weight of the
passenger?
Is it because of the air?
I don't know if it's because
of the weather, but it changes little by
little every day.
I see.
What is it?
This?
A science magazine?
What's that?
It's a manga by Soseki
Mutsume.
I'll read it.
Read it.
Thank you.
What color is this?
It's black.
Ears.
Is it called ears?
No.
Even if you call it that, it'll
look this way.
Little ears.
You're right.
Handwriting.
What's wrong?
Nothing.
Okay.
This one.
I think I'll like it.
Which one is better?
What should I do?
This one looks good, too.
I get lost when I rent it.
Yeah, I get lost.
I want to do it at the same
time.
Okay, let's do it.
Thank you.
Are you ready?
One, two, three.
It's the same.
This is a replica of the Gold
en Record.
This is the real one.
When aliens find it, it has a picture
that explains how to play it.
And inside, there's the sound of the
earth's rain and wind.
And there's greetings in English and Japanese.
Wow.
I think you'll be an astronaut in
the future.
But I don't think I'll make
it.
But I think you'll make it.
Really?
I heard there's an elementary school that
's close to the earth.
Will we bump into the earth someday?
Huh?
If we bump into it...
What are you reading?
It's interesting.
Interesting?
Why are you reading this?
Do you want to be an astronaut in
the future?
I don't know.
Does Akari say stupid things?
She does.
It's the first time I've heard
it.
So...
The sound of the earth...
Is there anything else?
I wonder.
Wind?
Water?
The ocean?
Let's race.
Let's run.
Okay.
Sure.
Let's go.
Wow.
Look.
It's so big.
What do you want to do when you
grow up?
When I grow up?
I don't know.
What do you want to do?
Well...
There are many things.
But I want to live alone.
I want to live in a place I
like.
I don't want to move.
I know.
Really?
I'm glad.
I don't want to move.
Yeah.
Are you still going to transfer?
I don't know.
What about your house?
I don't have a house anymore.
I'm going to stay in Tokyo.
That's good.
Hey.
Yeah?
It's 5 centimeters per second.
What?
The speed at which cherry blossoms fall.
It's 5 centimeters per second.
It's like snow.
Did you copy me?
Yeah, I did.
Wait a minute.
It's fast.
Wait.
Akari.
Takaki.
Next year, I hope we can see the
cherry blossoms together.
Shinohara.
Good morning.
It's a shame.
It's canceled.
I hope it will be sunny only in
the afternoon.
You want to do this outside, don't
you?
I want to do it.
Tono.
I knew it.
It's been a long time.
About 10 years.
It's amazing.
The probability of people meeting each other is
0.
0003%.
Is that so?
But, it may be even lower in a
competition.
I think so, too.
When I think about that person, I get
a call.
Or, I exchange phone numbers.
But, I can meet people whom I want
to meet.
That's amazing.
Really?
I think so.
Is that person your friend?
No.
He was my student.
I'm going to the airport.
It's a little cold.
It's in the morning.
Mr. Yuki is in the car with
the car.
I'm driving.
Good morning, TANAKO.
Good morning.
It's so cold.
Sumida?
Yes, Sumida.
Don't run.
You surprised me.
Are you drooling?
I'm not drooling.
It's rare.
I've never heard of it.
Really?
What is it?
It's sticky.
Right?
It only has your name on it.
What are you going to do?
I'm just hesitating.
You're hesitating all the time.
It's because you don't have a
bride in your head, right?
I'm sure you have a girlfriend in
Tokyo.
Yes, yes, yes, yes, yes.
In Tokyo.
Yes, yes.
Can I go home now?
Yes.
Surfing again today?
I'll do my best.
Don't you want to go home with
me?
No.
Are you okay?
I'm okay.
I'll go ahead.
Thank you.
This.
Yes?
Thank you.
Yes.
You like that kind of thing.
What is it?
Rock?
Rock.
Is it a foreign language?
I happened to hear it on the radio.
Really?
I bought it.
That's amazing.
You always drink that, don't you?
This.
Do you like it?
What?
Yes.
It's rare because it's not sold
in Tokyo.
You always drink that, don't you?
Do you like it?
Yes.
Raitan.
The stress of studying for the entrance exam.
Um...
Why did the teacher...
Don't change the subject.
I'm sorry.
About the cigarette...
I'm really sorry.
The teacher just happened to be there.
He wanted to leave Kushima anyway.
Then why did he come back?
Why?
I wonder if he thought it was the
same wherever he went.
Does that mean...
you couldn't get anywhere?
No.
I was in a hurry.
I was worried that I wouldn't be
able to move forward.
At that time, I thought I would die
if I stopped.
It won't shrink.
Tono.
I'm looking forward to what kind of
adult you will be.
What do you like about Tono?
What?
Why don't you ask him yourself?
I have an atmosphere that I can't
easily ask.
Tono is a troublesome guy.
No.
Tono is deep.
Deeper than us.
I feel like I'm looking far away.
For the time being, let's go to
karaoke together.
Let's go to the beach.
Let's confess.
That's the only way.
Really?
I really don't know.
Why?
What?
I think he knows what I like.
Even if he knows what I like, it
doesn't matter if I say it or
not, right?
What does it matter?
It's my life.
You're so cool.
Tono.
Tono's body was there.
Really?
Yes.
Can I sit here?
Excuse me.
You were called out today.
Did you hear that?
Yes.
I don't want to.
This.
Is it dead?
Yes.
What about you?
Tokyo University?
Yes.
I thought so.
Why?
Because you want to go far away?
I'm always lost.
Everyone is.
You too?
Yes.
No way.
You're not lost?
No, I'm not.
I'm just doing what I can.
I see.
Wow.
It's 5km per hour.
It's been a long time since I
've been on a plane.
Thank you.
Okay.
Don't be late.
I'll see you after school.
Okay.
Don't be late.
See you.
Thank you.
Okay.
Hey.
What?
If you don't mind, let's go
to karaoke after this.
What?
Karaoke.
Karaoke?
Let's go.
It's a song I can't sing.
Can I sing it?
What?
The song...
I can't sing it, but I'll
play it.
Okay.
I want to listen to it.
You're the first one to study abroad.
My boyfriend was doing long distance relationship.
Yes.
Do you know?
You were so serious and you were like
a person who was walking on a textbook.
Was I?
Yes.
But Ever since I had a long-
distance boyfriend, I've changed a lot.
I stopped saying the right thing.
My parents said I was bad.
But I like my sister more now.
I'm sure when I met him, I
think my sister's world has changed.
I don't know why we broke up.
I don't know how I feel.
What's wrong?
Nothing.
I don't know why.
Let me borrow your shoes.
Let me put them here for now.
I'll ask my family to pick them
up later.
Can I borrow your shoes?
Sure.
Let's walk today.
No, I'll walk by myself.
You can walk on the wall.
No, it's too close.
I want to walk with you.
See you.
I think
I understand why you're different from everyone
else.
It's a lonely journey that's beyond
imagination.
How far can we go like this?
How far can we go?
I realized at the same time that
he wasn't looking at
me.
I'm sorry.
Hey.
Good morning.
We're having a day off tomorrow.
It's been a while since we had
a meal.
Do you know?
Do you know what bamboo ice cream tastes
like?
I know.
Did you know that?
Yes, I did.
You haven't talked to anyone for a
long time, have you?
It's been a while since you went
out.
I don't know.
I can tell by your voice.
That's right.
That's why we have a chat.
You don't like it.
Don't say that.
Thank you.
I'm sorry.
I bought it yesterday.
I can't wait.
What's wrong?
I heard that your grades dropped again.
I hope the Earth is destroyed.
Even Nostradamus failed.
Is it destruction?
Is there an elementary school on Earth?
What's that?
Do you want to hear it?
Yes.
Do you know H991EV?
What is it?
Is it big?
Well, it's big.
What is it?
Thank you for your hard work.
The number of stars has fallen.
Is it big?
What?
The planet?
I think it's big because it's
a planet.
I see.
You've had a lot of friends, haven
't you?
Where is your hometown?
I don't have a hometown.
I see.
I'm from the Tenkin tribe.
So when I was a kid, I didn
't have any friends.
That's amazing.
You didn't have any at all?
Not at all.
No, I had one.
I see.
It's a good memory.
I'm still everyday.
At that time, I like things, places,
smells, words, and scenery.
I've met all of those things.
That's wonderful.
Are you still friends with that friend?
No, we don't see each other at
all now.
I see.
That's good.
I hope to see you again.
I hope so, too.
By the way, I'm going to have
a drink with an old friend of mine.
What do you think?
Can I?
It's Sumida.
You've grown up.
You haven't changed at all.
I haven't?
It's nostalgic.
I emailed Kanae to meet you.
He asked me to ask you one thing.
What is it?
I'm nervous.
Did you have a girlfriend in Tokyo when
you were in high school?
You always sent emails to someone on your
cell phone, didn't you?
No, I didn't.
It's just a diary.
A diary?
I'd like to know.
What did you write?
Nothing special.
What?
For example,
the sunset on the island is sometimes very
red, isn't it?
Well, it's not red, it's like
pink.
Yes, yes, yes.
Let's stop this.
No, no, no.
Continue.
When I see the sunset, I'm more
scared than I think it's beautiful.
I have a bad feeling about it.
Actually, when I see a beautiful scenery, there
are many things that I don't want
to happen.
On the contrary, there are good things when
I see a black cat.
And when I forget my PHS at
home, I always look at the shooting stars.
No, when I think about it now, it
's all a coincidence.
It's a coincidence, but I used to
believe that it wasn't a theory.
I used to believe that it was a
proof that I was connected to the world.
You're pulling it.
No, no, no.
No, no.
I laugh casually at times like this.
You don't have to laugh or cry
when you talk about the memories you cherish.
There was someone I was working with today.
I'm sorry for the sudden interruption.
No, the important thing I met a long
time ago is not memories, but everyday life.
I thought it would be nice to be
able to say that straight.
I'm Voyager, a planet explorer.
Welcome.
Thank you for coming.
It is said that there are more than
55,000 words that people meet in their
lifetime.
If you were to leave a word from
that, A word?
There was
an elementary school student named 1991E
V.
It was said that it might collide with
the earth on March 26, 2009.
You know well.
I used to read that article when I
was a kid.
I believed everything that was written in the
science book.
I was such a child.
It was a program.
But there are only a few things that
can be explained by science.
There are many things that can happen without
scientific proof.
The programmed code I designed is being operated
here.
Hello.
There are some things I want to develop
from now on.
Can you do me a favor?
Please let me do it.
That's great.
Thank you very much.
And one more thing.
I came up with this while talking to
Tono.
Hello?
Mom?
I just left the station.
I'm fine.
I want to walk a little.
I'm tired.
Hey, Akari.
I wanted to ask you something.
Akari's name is named after Ak
arui.
I've never heard of it.
It's definitely named after Akarui.
Am I bright?
If you're with me, you'll feel
bright.
Thank you.
I can see the stars, but I can
't see the moon.
It's a new moon today, so I
can't see it.
Let me explain the new moon.
The black circle here is the new moon.
The moon is the same as the earth,
and it doesn't shine by itself.
The moon looks bright because it reflects the
sun's light.
I see.
So I can't see the moon.
But the night sky gets darker in the
new moon, so it's easier to see
the Milky Way.
Can I see it today?
The city is too bright to see it
in Tokyo.
I see.
I want to see it with you someday.
I want to see it.
This is my birthday present.
It's a little late.
You're giving me this?
Thank you.
I'll treasure it for the rest of
my life.
If you close your eyes and open them
again, you'll be able to see the
stars.
Really?
Let's do it.
Close your eyes for 10 seconds.
Okay.
It's the Milky Way.
It's true.
Wait a minute.
Takagi Hello, Takagi.
What's wrong?
I can't go to junior high school
with you.
What?
You said you were going to move to
a new school.
You said you wanted to go to a
new school, but you said you had to
wait until you grew up.
I see.
That's enough.
I'm sorry, Takagi.
Takagi, how are you?
How are you doing in junior high school?
I think you've made a lot of
new friends.
It's been six months since I last
saw you.
Do you still remember me?
The night of Tochigi is pitch
black, so the moon and stars look brighter
and clearer than Tokyo.
There's a big cherry tree near my
house.
In spring, the petals fall to the ground
at 5 cm per second.
I hope I can see it with you.
Takagi, thank you for your answer.
I'm glad you're doing well.
I laughed a lot about the math teacher.
The lemon milk I wrote in my letter
was finally served for lunch.
I can't tell anyone, but it tasted
very subtle.
I'd like to ask Takagi for
his impression.
I was surprised that Takagi moved to
Kagoshima this time.
Tochigi and Kagoshima are very
far away, aren't they?
I can't even imagine how far apart
they are.
I'm very happy that you came to
see me before I moved to Kagoshima.
I have a lot to tell you, too.
I'm waiting for you at Iw
afune Station at 7 p.
m.
on the promised day.
Please be careful.
I'll let you
know.
The Omiya-boume
station train is only 28 minutes late due
to snow.
We apologize for the inconvenience.
The train is arriving.
The train is delayed, so this train will
stop for about 10 minutes at Toei
station.
We apologize for the inconvenience, but please
wait for a while.
I will write a letter to Vincent for
the first time.
I'm going to tell him directly if
I see him tomorrow, but I'm writing
this letter now in case I can't.
I don't know what it means to
be an adult yet.
But someday, I want to be a person
who doesn't feel embarrassed even if I
meet Akari somewhere by chance.
I want to promise that to Akari.
Finally, I've
always liked Akari.
Please stay healthy in the future as well.
Thank you very much.
The train is delayed, so this
train will stop for about 10 minutes at
Toei station.
You're exaggerating.
I'm not exaggerating.
Let's go see the cherry blossoms.
Oh, you mean the letter?
Yes.
Let's go.
Akari.
What did your mom say?
She said, don't worry, I'll be
home by any time.
She left a letter.
What?
It's the same as mine.
It's the same?
Yes.
It's almost time to move, isn't
it?
Yes.
It's next week, isn't it?
Kagoshima, huh?
It's far, isn't it?
Yes.
Tochigi was far, too.
We can't go back.
Yes.
School life?
It's fun, isn't it?
It's fun.
What do you like to do?
I like to play soccer.
Soccer?
Yes.
Really?
Let's take a look.
Wait.
It's
snowing.
My pants...
It's cold.
It's dangerous.
It's fluffy snow.
Yes.
Akari, do you remember the story of
the asteroid approaching the earth?
Yes.
It's 1991EV, isn't it?
Why do you remember?
It's a short story.
Yes.
According to the calculation, it was
March 26, 2009.
I'll calculate it.
Yes.
According to the calculation, it was just before
you turned 30.
30 years old.
You've grown up.
I'm waiting for you, Takaki.
It's frozen.
Great.
It's snowing on my hand.
Yes.
If you had grown up, you could have
died on March 26, 2009.
What?
Then, let's meet here.
Here?
If you had grown up, we'll celebrate
the end of the world together.
I see.
I'll come at 7 o'clock.
No.
The world won't end.
You'll grow up.
I hope so.
Yes.
March 26, 2009 Bye.
Good night.
Thank you for boarding.
The exit is on the right.
It'll be snowing soon.
Please check your luggage.
The door is closing.
Please be careful.
Takaki.
The door is closing.
Please be careful.
See you later.
It's getting closer.
It's going to be snowing.
We can't catch the piping.
What should we do?
We can't finish the event today.
What's wrong?
It's been a while since the wax
was added.
I overlooked it.
Where is it?
I'm glad you made it in time.
I'm sorry.
Here are 50 more.
Thank you.
Are you okay?
Yes.
I'm sorry.
Captain.
I'm sorry to bother you on such
a snowy day.
I'm sorry.
It's okay.
I've wanted to come here for a
long time.
I'm glad.
Really?
Would you like to see the inside?
Can I?
Sure.
Today's Planetarium is a live commentary.
Do you have time?
Yes, I do.
It's amazing.
When was the last time I saw a
planetarium?
There are new discoveries when you grow up.
I see.
It's the day we made a promise.
A promise?
Look, it's today.
The day the Earth will be destroyed.
Destroyed?
Shino told you, didn't she?
That the planet will fall.
What?
Today?
No, no, no.
I believe you.
You'll understand when you understand.
Well, yes.
Well, enjoy yourself.
Thank you.
Hello, everyone.
Thank you for coming today.
Now, let's start the planetarium.
Let's get started.
This is the night sky of today, March
26, 2009.
I'm sure you've seen the moon.
Voyager 1 and Voyager 2 are
traveling even further than the moon.
Voyager 1 and Voyager 2 set
off from Earth in 1977 and are
now 156 km away from Earth.
Voyager has a golden record, where the
sounds and words of the Earth are recorded.
It is a message for someone who may
be somewhere in the universe.
I wonder if someone will find it someday.
Now, Voyager 1 and 2 will never
return to Earth.
Voyager 1 and 2 will never return
to Earth.
Voyager 2 and 3 will continue to
travel in different directions for a very long
time.
If you look up at the night sky,
try to remember that Voyager is still
traveling somewhere in the universe.
Now, your room
will be bright.
Thank you very much.
It's beautiful, isn't it?
It's like a petal.
Well, it's 5 cm in diameter.
Huh?
It's a petal.
It has a falling speed, doesn't it?
5 cm per second.
Wow.
Is that true?
I don't know.
It's a speed I came up with
a long time ago.
Wow.
Thank you very much.
It's
okay.
I'm going to give this notebook to
Takaki-kun later.
Takaki-kun told me before.
The reflection of the sun is what makes
the moon shine.
When I heard that, I thought it was
like Takaki-kun and me.
I've always hated my name, Akari.
I've always hated my name.
I was always thought of as a dark
girl.
I was embarrassed that my name didn't
suit me.
So, when Takaki-kun told me
that I was bright, I was very happy.
When we're together, we feel bright, too.
The words Takaki-kun told me
at that time still make me bright.
Takaki-kun was the sun for
me.
Takaki-kun's words and...
Akari.
Let's go.
When Takaki-kun called out to
me, I became strong.
I like you, Takaki-kun.
Please be well.
Tomo-san.
I'm glad I asked you.
I'll ask you again.
I was nervous, so I couldn't speak
well.
No, it was a nice voice.
Tomo-san's voice is sincere
and honest.
Thank you.
I'm closing today, so please come home
before the train stops.
I understand.
Thank you.
The train will stop for 2 minutes.
I'm sorry for the inconvenience.
This train is bound for Honma-
sui.
The train will stop at Honma-
sui in 3 minutes.
Please be careful on the next train.
The next stop is Minami-s
ui.
Thank you.
Minami-sui If
it's just a small glass, anyone
should be fine.
On a night when the stars are about
to fall, don't lie to yourself.
One more time.
Don't be depressed.
Let's go.
What should we do?
Yes, it's like this.
Great.
Thank you.
It's done.
Is there anything wrong?
No, no.
I think your face has changed a little.
What?
Well, if there is, I'm 30 years
old.
I'm 30 years old.
Congratulations.
I couldn't keep up with my age.
If you're 30 years old, you're
just around the world.
Even if you started walking at the age
of one, you've walked that far by
the age of 30.
You're making good progress.
Congratulations.
I'm sorry to say this all of
a sudden.
Can you tell me a little bit about
yourself?
It's not about work, it's about
yourself.
Of course.
I'm sorry.
No.
Go ahead.
I used to make a promise to someone.
On March 26, 2009, I made a promise
to meet the end of the world together.
It was 16 years ago.
It was a promise on that day.
I don't remember if I said the
word promise properly.
I said, maybe.
On that day, at the promised place.
But that person didn't come.
Of course, the world didn't end.
Nothing happened.
On the way home, I was wondering why
I wanted to see him again.
I was wondering why.
I wanted to talk to him one more
time.
Anything.
For example, long time no see.
How have you been?
I just wanted to talk to him.
I wanted to talk to him.
And that person said, I wanted
him to say something.
People meet more than 50,000 words in
their life.
I don't need that.
I wish I could remember only one important
thing that I need, but I forgot it
and it didn't stay anywhere.
On a
snowy day, I heard about the same
promise from the person who was sitting in
that seat.
But that person said he wouldn't go
because he wanted the other person to
forget that promise.
I want him to live happily so that
he won't remember the past.
I'm sure he'll be fine.
Takaki-kun.
I'm sure you'll be fine.
You'll be fine from now on.
How is he?
I'm sure he'll be fine.
You'll be fine from now on.
I'm sure you'll be fine.
You'll
be fine from now on.
I'm sure you'll be fine.
You'll be fine from now on.
I'm a little nervous.
I'm nervous too.
I'm nervous because I'm not sure
if he'll go.
How long will he be back?
Well, it's been about five years since
we got married.
It's just a few days away.
I'm sure it'll be soon.
Yeah, it's fast.
Oh!
What?
Are you all right?
It took a long time.
I should have kept it.
It's cute.
It's good, isn't it?
Simple.
Yeah.
I'm glad.
Thank you.
Yeah.
But that's the hardest part.
My sister used to say that.
Yeah.
When you think you like someone you like,
you say you like them.
That's right.
Take care.
Yeah.
Someday.
Let's go for a walk.
Yeah.
Long time no see.
How are you?
I'm fine.
Thank you.
Thank you for everything.
Yeah.
See you.
Mizuno.
You know the name of the person in
the company.
You remember their full name.
You don't mishear anything.
You don't cheat with random answers.
You don't cheat.
And...
The important thing is that you look at
each other and talk.
You don't look at each other.
You're completely different from yourself.
I liked everything about you.
You're late.
Sorry.
No.
I'm not late.
Yeah.
I'll remember everything.
Thank you for being there for me.
Take care.